pythonprogramming.net 2019-12-14

# Python Programming Tutorials

Last updated: March 1st 2018

### GDPR

#### Personal data collected, and why!

  1. Username you choose - This is how you are identified on the website
  2. Password - this is how we confirm it's really you.
  3. Email - this is how you can recover your account. We do not require email validation, you can feel free to make this up if you wanted, just know you can't recover your account if so.
  4. Tutorials you've completed - When you click the "next tutorial" button at the bottom of a tutorial, that tutorial is marked as "completed" by your account.
  5. Finally, we track whether or not you've signed up to +=1. If you have, the date and time of your purchase is logged, the last name of the PayPal account, the username associated with this name, the payment itself, and the transaction ID is stored.

I also use Google Adsense and Google Analytics, which collects various data on you too. Via Google Analytics, I have opted for the lowest user and event data retention available on their platform, which is 14 months. More info on data retention: https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196?authuser=0.

Also, via google analytics, IPs are anonymized.

#### How long your data is retained:

  1. All of the above data is retained indefinitely (except for Google Analytics and Google Adsense, I really cannot speak to their full practices, just that I chose the 14-month retention in Google Analytics), unless otherwise requested in writing.
  2. Within Google Analytics, I have set the data retention to 14 months, and to reset on new activity. So, data stored via Google Analytics is removed 14 months automatically after you *stop* using the website. If you continue to use the website, then the data's expiration renews to be the CURRENT time, plus 14 months.

#### Who we share your data with?

  1. To monetize the website, I make use of Google Adsense, which uses tracking cookies, tracking its own data on you.
  2. The data found under the above "Personal data collected, and why!" section is not shared with any other entities, except in the case of a PayPal transaction where we compare details of the transaction on our end with PayPal's details of that same transaction to confirm its legitimacy.

#### What are my rights with my data??

  1. If you want to see all of the data we have on you, make a request to Harrison@pythonprogramming.net
  2. If you want all of your data permanently scrubbed, deleted, never to be seen again from the website...make a request to Harrison@pythonprogramming.net for this service.

Resuming the original privacy policy: 

PythonProgramming ("us", "we", or "our") operates the http://pythonprogramming.net website (the "Service").

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information when you use our Service.

We will not use or share your information with anyone except as described in this Privacy Policy.

**We use your Personal Information for providing and improving the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.** Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible at https://pythonprogramming.net/about/tos/

**Information Collection And Use**

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you. Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to, your email address, name ("Personal Information").

We collect this information for the purpose of providing the Service, identifying and communicating with you, responding to your requests/inquiries, servicing your purchase orders, and improving our services.

**Log Data**

We collect information that your browser sends whenever you visit our Service ("Log Data"). This Log Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol ("IP") address, browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages and other statistics.

In addition, we may use third party services such as Google Analytics that collect, monitor and analyze this type of information in order to increase our Service's functionality. These third party service providers have their own privacy policies addressing how they use such information.

**Cookies**

Cookies are files with a small amount of data, which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a web site and transferred to your device. We use cookies to collect information in order to improve our services for you.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. The Help feature on most browsers provide information on how to accept cookies, disable cookies or to notify you when receiving a new cookie.

If you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some features of our Service and we recommend that you leave them turned on.

**DoubleClick Cookie**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other web sites on the Internet.

You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the [Google Ads Settings](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/ "Google Ads Settings") web page.

**Do Not Track Disclosure**

We do not support Do Not Track ("DNT"). Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked.

You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

**Service Providers**

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service, to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services and/or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Information only to perform specific tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use your information for any other purpose.

**Communications**

We may use your Personal Information to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by contacting us.

**Compliance With Laws**

We will disclose your Personal Information where required to do so by law or subpoena or if we believe that such action is necessary to comply with the law and the reasonable requests of law enforcement or to protect the security or integrity of our Service.

**Security**

The security of your Personal Information is important to us, and we strive to implement and maintain reasonable, commercially acceptable security procedures and practices appropriate to the nature of the information we store, in order to protect it from unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure.

However, please be aware that no method of transmission over the internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure and we are unable to guarantee the absolute security of the Personal Information we have collected from you.

**International Transfer**

Your information, including Personal Information, may be transferred to - and maintained on - computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside United States and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the information, including Personal Information, to United States and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

**Links To Other Sites**

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

**Children's Privacy**

Only persons age 18 or older have permission to access our Service, or if a legal guardian or parent of the user gives consent. Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 13 ("Children").

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If you are a parent or guardian and you learn that your Children have provided us with Personal Information, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Information from a children under age 13 without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

**Changes To This Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is effective as of January 22, 2015 and will remain in effect except with respect to any changes in its provisions in the future, which will be in effect immediately after being posted on this page.

We reserve the right to update or change our Privacy Policy at any time and you should check this Privacy Policy periodically. Your continued use of the Service after we post any modifications to the Privacy Policy on this page will constitute your acknowledgment of the modifications and your consent to abide and be bound by the modified Privacy Policy.

If we make any material changes to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you either through the email address you have provided us, or by placing a prominent notice on our website.

**Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact Harrison@pythonprogramming.net.
